Preliminary Guide to the Takey Crist Papers, 1944-2002 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Takey Crist papers 1944-2002 and undated
Crist, Takey
64.6 linear feet Extent: 21,903 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00270
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The majority of the collection is open for research. Accession 2002-0149 is closed to research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Most of the audiovisual components in this accession are not immediately accessible because they require further processing before use. Unless otherwise noted, Technical Services staff need to reformat for use copies of the films.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Takey Crist Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from 2002-2007.
Biographical Note
Physician in Jacksonville, N.C., and long-time supporter of women's reproductive rights. Operator of the Crist Clinic for Women, which provides a variety of women's healthcare services, including abortions.
Collection Overview
Accession 2002-149(778 items, 22.0 linear feet; dated 1971-2001) contains files of abortion, pregnancy, and hysterectomy malpractice cases in which Crist served as a consultant or codefendant along with the Crist Clinic. There is also printed material on reproductive topics. Also includes 2 VHS videocassettes; 6 color slides; 30 black-and-white and 2 color photographs. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Addition 2003-007 (67 items, 7.3 linear ft.; undated) is composed of 16mm films used by "Crist Clinic Audio Visuals" in health education programs (undated). The clinic also offered the films for sale or rent to educators, students, doctors, parents, and others. The majority of the films focus on sex education for children and teenagers. Topics include puberty and menstruation, sex and sexuality, sexual orientation, lifestyle choices, and sexually transmitted diseases. Other topics include abortion; pregnancy and childbirth; infant care and nutrition; marriage and parenting; and drug and alcohol abuse.
Addition 2003-118 is comprised of materials related to the issue of abortion and the anti-abortion movement, and consists primarily of documents pertaining to lawsuits involving Dr. Crist as a litigant or witness, including correspondence, transcripts, depositions, photographs, and other legal papers (1975-1993). Also contains files on organizations including the National Abortion Federation and NARAL (1982-2002 and undated); subject files; research material assembled by Dr. Crist, including publications; correspondence; and newspaper clippings.
Addition 2004-098 (10,158 items, 16.7 lin. ft.; dated 1962-1980s, bulk 1962-1972) comprises personal and professional correspondence and subject files (1960s-early 1970s) documenting Crist's medical training, internship, residency, and then his position as Assistant Professor at UNC Chapel Hill, especially his involvement in increased access to therapeutic abortions and health services; the development of abortion techniques; and sex and contraceptive education on and off campus. Also includes writings and speeches; patient notes (redacted); grant, research, and conference files; and printed materials, including clippings, articles, and pamphlets. Some anti-abortion materials in boxes 3-5 contain graphic imagery.
Addition 2006-098 (400 items, 0.8 lin. ft.; dated 1944-1978) consists of personal files, including medical licenses and report cards; abortion series files, 1971-2000, including general correspondence, correspondence concerning the National Organization of Women and the National Coalition of Abortion Providers; newsletters; printed material about the ordinance lawsuit; photographs of demonstrators, 1985; and subject files, 1960-1972, created while at UNC including files about conferences, homosexuality, consultation work for family planning, studies conducted while at UNC Medical School, speaking engagements on sex education; and Health Education Clinic finances. Interfiled in existing collection.
Addition 2007-043 (13,125 items, 21.0 linear feet) contains subject files that chronicle the history of the Crist Clinic from the opening of the clinic in 1973 to the early 21st century. The majority of the files contain Takey Crist's clippings on medical topics and issues relating to sex education and women's health care. Many files also refer to issues of significance for physicians running a private clinic.
Subject Headings
Crist, Takey; Crist Clinic for Women; National Abortion Federation (U.S.); National Abortion Rights Action League; Women -- Health and hygiene -- North Carolina; Women's health services -- North Carolina; Women's health services -- North Carolina -- Chapel Hill; Abortion services -- North Carolina; Abortion services -- Employees; Hysterectomy; Pregnancy; Pro-life movement; Abortion; Malpractice -- North Carolina; Physicians -- Malpractice -- United States; Obstetricians -- Malpractice -- United States; Gynecologists -- Malpractice -- United States; Science films; Sex instruction -- United States; Sex instruction -- North Carolina -- Chapel Hill; Sex instruction for children -- United States; Sex instruction for teenagers -- United States; Sex instruction for teenagers -- North Carolina; Hygiene, Sexual -- Study and teaching -- United States; Hygiene, Sexual -- Study and teaching -- North Carolina; Health education -- United States; Health education -- North Carolina; Family life education; Obstetrics; Sex; Marriage -- United States; Sexually transmitted diseases; Sexual orientation; Puberty; Legal files; Speeches; Clippings; Pamphlets; Videocassettes; Color slides; Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs; Motion pictures (visual works); Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
Preliminary Description of Unprocessed Collection
- Accession 2002-0149
  Accession (778 items, 22.0 linear feet; dated 1971-2001) contains files of abortion, pregnancy, and hysterectomy malpractice cases in which Crist served as a consultant or codefendant along with the Crist Clinic. There is also printed material on reproductive topics. Also includes 2 VHS videocassettes; 6 color slides; 30 black-and-white and 2 color photographs. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
  Accession 2002-0149 is closed to research.
- Accession 2003-0007
  Addition (67 items, 7.3 linear ft.; undated) consists of 67 16mm films used by "Crist Clinic Audio Visuals" in health education programs (undated). The clinic also offered the films for sale or rent to educators, students, doctors, parents, and others. The majority of the films focus on sex education for children and teenagers. Topics include puberty and menstruation, sex and sexuality, sexual orientation, lifestyle choices, and sexually transmitted diseases. Other topics include abortion; pregnancy and childbirth; infant care and nutrition; marriage and parenting; and drug and alcohol abuse. Arranged in alphabetical order by title. Reels are individually numbered and are not boxed together but housed separately.
  [Most of the films in this accession are not immediately accessible, because they require further processing before use. Unless otherwise noted, Technical Services staff need to reformat for use copies of the films. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this material.]
  - About Sex, 1972; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (800 ft.) (TRT: 23:00) (Reel 39)
    Use Copies: DVD use copy available.
  - Alcohol: Crisis for the Unborn, 1977-1979; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (400 ft.) (TRT: 12:00) (Reel 26)
  - Am I Normal? 1979; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (800 ft.) (TRT: 23:00) (Reel 38)
  - Are You Listening?; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1600 ft.) (TRT: 44:00) (Reel 3)
  - Are You Ready for Sex? 1976; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (900 ft.) (TRT: 30:00) (Reel 31)
  - Better By Choice; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (600 ft.) (TRT: 17:00) (Reel 63)
  - Born Hooked, 1974-1979; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (500 ft.) (TRT: 14:00) (Reel 61)
  - BS Love Counselor, Part 1; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (200 ft.) (TRT: 6:00) (Reel 24)
  - BS Love Counselor, Part 2; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (200 ft.) (TRT: 6:00) (Reel 25)
  - A Chance of Love, 1972; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (850 ft.) (TRT: 23:00) (Reel 32)
  - Confidence by Choice; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (400 ft.) (TRT: 12:00) (Reel 17)
  - Contraceptive Methods: Choice with Understanding, 1978; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (910 ft.) (TRT: 29:00) (Reel 20)
  - Dear Diary, 1981; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (800 ft.) (TRT: 23:00) (Reel 33)
  - Diagnosis of Vulvovaginatis; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (750 ft.) (TRT: 18:00) (Reel 46)
  - Don't Tell the Cripples About Sex, Part 1, 1973; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (500 ft.) (TRT: 14:00) (Reel 44)
  - Don't Tell the Cripples About Sex, Part 2, 1973; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (800 ft.) (TRT: 23:00) (Reel 45)
  - Early Homosexual Fears, 1974-1977; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (400 ft.) (TRT: 12:00) (Reel 59)
  - Feeding Baby Through the First Year, 1974; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (700 ft.) (TRT: 20:00) (Reel 42)
  - Free, 1970; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (450 ft.) (TRT: 12:00) (Reel 57)
  - From Menarche To Marriage; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1200 ft.) (TRT: 34:00) (Reel 30)
  - Give It a Try; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1200 ft.) (TRT: 34:00) (Reel 23)
  - Guess Who's Pregnant, Part 1, 1977; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1000 ft.) (TRT: 28:00) (Reel 27)
  - Guess Who's Pregnant, Part 2, 1977; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1050 ft.) (Reel 28)
  - Happy Birthday, 1975; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (500 ft.) (TRT: 14:00) (Reel 49)
  - Holding, 1970; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (491 ft.) (TRT: 14:00) (Reel 67)
  - Human Sexuality and Communication, Part 1, Copy 1; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1200 ft.) (TRT: 34:00) (Reel 10)
  - Human Sexuality and Communication, Part 1, Copy 2; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1200 ft.) (TRT: 34:00) (Reel 11)
  - Human Sexuality and Communication, Part 2, Copy 1; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1200 ft.) (TRT: 34:00) (Reel 8)
  - Human Sexuality and Communication, Part 2, Copy 2; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1200 ft.) (TRT: 34:00) (Reel 9)
  - I Change, I Am the Same, Preview Reel 2; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1000 ft.) (TRT: 28:00) (Reel 13)
  - Infant Nutrition: A Gift of Love, 1942; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (775 ft.) (TRT: 21:00) (Reel 36)
  - Infant Nutrition: A Gift of Love, 1942, Copy 2; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (775 ft.) (TRT: 21:00) (Reel 37)
  - It Couldn't Happen to me, 1973; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1000 ft.) (TRT: 28:00) (Reel 19)
  - It Couldn't Happen to me, Copy 2, 1973; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1000 ft.) (TRT: 28:00) (Reel 4)
  - It's My Turn, 1972; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (725 ft.) (TRT: 19:00) (Reel 47)
  - Modern Obstetrics: Cesarean Section, 1975; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (775 ft.) (TRT: 21:00) (Reel 50)
  - Modern Obstetrics: Normal Delivery, 1964; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1000 ft.) (TRT: 28:00) (Reel 15)
  - Modern Obstetrics: Pre-Eclampsia, Eclampsia, 1972; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1000 ft.) (TRT: 28:00) (Reel 16)
  - Naturally A Girl, 1973; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (500 ft.) (TRT: 14:00) (Reel 62)
  - Normal Labor and Delivery, 1981; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (792 ft.) (TRT: 22:00) (Reel 48)
  - Old Enough to Know, 1974; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1100 ft.) (TRT: 20:00) (Reel 5)
  - Old Enough to Know, 1974; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (750 ft.) (Reel 52)
  - Parent to Child about Sex, 1974; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1000 ft.) (TRT: 28:00) (Reel 18)
  - Parents Voices, 1973-1976; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (450 ft.) (TRT: 12:00) (Reel 58)
  - Phenomena of Early Development, 1960; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (500 ft.) (TRT: 14:00) (Reel 40)
  - The Puzzle Children, Part 1, 1976-1977; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1200 ft.) (TRT: 34:00) (Reel 6)
  - The Puzzle Children, Part 2, 1976-1977; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1050 ft.) (Reel 21)
  - Running My Way, 1981; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (880 ft.) (TRT: 28:00) (Reel 35)
  - Seasons of Sexuality, 1980; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (500 ft.) (TRT: 14:00) (Reel 66)
  - Sex Fears, 1974-1977; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (510 ft.) (TRT: 15:00) (Reel 56)
  - Sex Games, Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (600 ft.) (TRT: 17:00) (Reel 53)
  - Sex Mis-education, 1974-1977; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (400 ft.) (TRT: 12:00) (Reel 54)
  - Sex Morals, 1974-1977; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (490 ft.) (TRT: 30:00) (Reel 55)
  - Teen Sexuality, 1975; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1050 ft.) (TRT: 30:00) (Reel 7)
  - Teenage Father; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1000 ft.) (28:00) (Reel 34)
  - Teenage Father, Copy 2; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1000 ft.) (28:00) (Reel 12)
  - Tempo 78, Abortion; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1200 ft.) (TRT: 34:00) (Reel 14)
  - A Three Letter Word for Love, 1971; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (900 ft.) (TRT: 30:00) (Reel 29)
  - Too Soon Blues, 1972; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (1000 ft.) (TRT: 28:00) (Reel 22)
  - Touching, 1972; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (515 ft.) (TRT: 16:00) (Reel 65)
  - The Trying Time, 1974; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (775 ft.) (TRT:20:00) (Reel 43)
  - Vasectomy Technologies; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (600 ft.) (TRT: 17:00) (Reel 41)
  - VD - The Plague of Love; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (750 ft.) (Reel 2)
  - Vir Amat, 1970; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (500 ft.) (TRT: 14:00) (Reel 60)
  - What is Sexually Normal?; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (800 ft.) (TRT: 23:00) (Reel 1)
  - Woman Child, 1979; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (500 ft.) (TRT: 14:00) (Reel 64)
  - Young, Single, and Pregnant, 1973; Screening print, 16 mm, sd., col., (700 ft.) (TRT: 18:00) (Reel 51)
  - Master copies (Box AV1)
- Accession 2003-0118
  Addition comprises materials related to the issue of abortion and the anti-abortion movement, and consists primarily of documents pertaining to lawsuits involving Dr. Crist as a litigant or witness, including correspondence, transcripts, depositions, photographs, and other legal papers (1975-1993). Also contains files on organizations including the National Abortion Federation and NARAL (1982-2002 and undated); subject files; research material assembled by Dr. Crist, including publications; correspondence; and newspaper clippings.
  [Accession is restricted. Patrons must sign a waiver concerning privacy rights. Contact Research Services.]
  - Abortion Series
    - Lawsuits
      - Crist v. Henderson, including correspondence and depositions, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
      - Crist v. Henderson, including photographs and correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 2)
      - Crist v. Henderson correspondence, 1986 (Box 3)
      - Crist v. Tierno, including transcripts and correspondence, 1983 (Box 3)
      - Crist v. Tierno, including correspondence and sent materials, 1984 (Box 4)
      - Crist v. Tierno, including correspondence, depositions, and legal bills, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
      - Crist v. Royal, including legal bills, and legal papers, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
      - Crist v. Royal, including correspondence, depositions, complaints, newspaper clippings, and affidavits, 1987-1988 (Box 6)
      - North Carolina v. Shreve, including legal bills, investigations, articles, and correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 6)
      - North Carolina v. Shreve, including correspondence and transcripts, 1988-1990 (Box 7)
      - Ordinance Lawsuit, including correspondence, articles, legal materials, and demonstrator photographs, 1984-1990 (Box 7)
      - Ordinance Lawsuit, demonstrator photographs, 1984-1987 (Box 8)
      - Ordinance Lawsuit, demonstrator photographs, 1988-1993 (Box 9)
      - Whittington v. DHR, including correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box 9)
      - Parental consent law, 1995-1996 (Box 9)
      - Parental consent law, 1995-1996 (Box 10)
      - Massachusetts v. Edelin transcripts, 1975 (Box 10)
      - Fargo Women's Health Organization Inc. v. Patricia Larson, et al., 1985 (Box 10)
      - Wisconsin v. Horn, 1985 (Box 11)
      - Feminist Women's Health Center v. Dottie Roberts et al., 1986 (Box 11)
      - Mitchell Williams v. George Schultz, et al., 1986 (Box 11)
      - Legal Opinion in Thornburgh et al. v. American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists (Box 11)
    - Research Files
      - Reproductive Rights Law Reporter (Box 11)
        Includes Index and Glossary, Articles, Supreme Court Cases, Abortion, Contraception, Sterilization, Clinic Violence, and Fertility sections.
      - Publications on abortion, 1973-1985 (Box 11)
      - Publications on abortion, 1973-1992 (Box 12)
      - Abortion Reference Index Illustrated (Box 12)
        Vertical file of materials for use by clinic visitors; contains sections entitled Financial, Anti-Abortion Strategy, Statistics, Speeches, National Support, Health and TA's, New York Times, Battered, Jefferson, Polls, Catholics, Edelin, Violence, Politics, Nathanson, Teenagers, 10 TA Facts, Organizations, and Law.
      - Abortion Update, 1969-1974 (Box 12)
        Research files assembled each year by Crist to organize scientific and medical literature published that year.
      - Abortion Update, 1975-1989 and undated (Box 13)
      - North Carolina Department of Human Resources, North Carolina Reported Abortions, 1972-1988, vol. I-III (Box 13)
    - Correspondence
      - 1971-1976 and undated (Box 13)
      - 1977-1981 and undated (Box 14)
      - 1981-1986 (Box 15)
      - 1987-1997 (Box 16)
      - Hate Mail, 1974-1994 (Box 17)
      - Anti-Abortion Mail, Phonebook Ads (Box 17)
    - Subject Files
      - Anti-Abortion Publicity (Box 18)
      - Joseph Scheidler (Box 18)
        Includes files called Lawsuits, Background, Tactics and Violence, and related to Jacksonville Visit (Correspondence, Announcements, Scheidler's Speech, and Media Coverage).
      - Abortion Rights March, including clippings and correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 18)
      - Abortion Rights March, including clippings and correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 19)
      - Anti-Abortion Counseling Centers (Box 19)
      - Birthchoice (Box 19)
      - NC Right to Life (Box 19)
      - Pro-Life Merchandise (Box 19)
      - Women Exploited by Abortion (WEBA) (Box 19)
      - Bauman, Robert (Box 19)
      - Falwell, Jerry (Box 19)
      - Gunn, David, 1993 murder (Box 19)
      - Helms, Jesse, Political Cartoons (Box 19)
      - Mason, Mary, anti-abortion activist (Box 19)
      - Photographs, demonstrators, 1985 Dec. 23, Pray for Crist (Box 19)
      - Reagan, Ronald (Box 19)
      - Robertson, Pat (Box 19)
      - Swaggart, Jimmy (Box 19)
      - Anti-Abortion Cartoons (Box 19)
      - Sex Education/Pornography (Box 19)
    - Organizations
      - National Abortion Federation
        - NAF Facts and Handouts (Box 19)
        - NAF - Resources and References (Box 20)
        - Networks (Box 20)
        - General files, 1982-1984 (Box 20)
        - Firebombing, arson, and violence, 1985 (Box 21)
        - General files, 1984-1988 (Box 21)
        - General files, 1988-1993 (Box 22)
        - Going to Court Against Antiabortion Action: A Model Pleadings Book, 1987 (Box 22)
        - The First Amendment Book: A Guide for Abortion Providers and their Attorneys, 1988 (Box 22)
      - National Coalition of Abortion Providers
        - 1990-1991 (Box 22)
        - 1992-2002 (Box 23)
      - National Abortion Rights Action League
        - NARAL Anti-Abortion clippings (Box 23)
        - NARAL News (Box 23)
        - NARAL-NC (Box 24)
        - NARAL, Abortion Law Reporter, References and Indexes (1) through Information, Records (8) (Box 24)
        - NARAL, Abortion Law Reporter, Informed Consent (9) through Updates (17) (Box 25)
      - Abortion Rights Mobilization (Box 25)
      - ACCESS (Box 25)
      - Accord (Box 25)
      - American Association of Pro-Life Obstetricians and Gynecologists (Box 25)
      - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 25)
      - Bill Baird Institute (Box 25)
      - The Body Politic (Box 25)
      - Burke County Citizens for CHOICE (Box 25)
      - Capital Choice (Box 26)
      - Catholics for a Free Choice (Box 26)
      - Center for Reproductive Law and Policy (Box 26)
      - Choices (Box 26)
      - Feminist Majority Foundation (Box 26)
      - Feminist Women's Health Center (Box 26)
      - Alan Gutmacher Institute (Box 26)
      - Life Dynamics (Box 26)
      - Christian Life Commission of the Southern Baptist Convention (Box 27)
      - North Carolina Civil Liberties Union (Box 27)
      - North Carolina Coalition for Choice (Box 27)
      - North Carolina Medical Society (Box 27)
      - National Organization of Women (Box 27)
      - Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights (Box 27)
      - Bob Packwood (Box 27)
      - Planned Parenthood (Box 27)
      - Presbyterians Pro-Life (Box 27)
      - ProChoice Resource Center (Box 27)
      - People for the American Way (Box 27)
      - South Mountain Women's Health Alliance (Box 27)
      - Women's Health Action and Mobilization (WHAM) (Box 27)
      - The Christian Activist (Box 27)
      - Life and Family News (Box 27)
    - Newspaper Clippings
      - 1970-1977 and undated (Box 27)
      - 1978-1983 (Box 28)
      - 1984-1989 June (Box 29)
      - 1989 July-1990 (Box 30)
      - 1991-1993 (Box 31)
      - 1994-1997 (Box 32)
- Accession, 2004 (2004-0098), 27 Boxes
  Addition (10,158 items, 16.7 lin. ft.; dated 1962-1980s, bulk 1962-1972) comprises personal and professional correspondence and subject files (1960s-early 1970s) documenting Crist's medical training, internship, residency, and then his position as Assistant Professor at UNC Chapel Hill, especially his involvement in increased access to therapeutic abortions and health services; the development of abortion techniques; and sex and contraceptive education on and off campus. Also includes writings and speeches; patient notes (redacted); grant, research, and conference files; and printed materials, including clippings, articles, and pamphlets. Some anti-abortion materials in boxes 3-5 contain graphic imagery.
  Accession is restricted. Patrons must sign a waiver concerning privacy rights. Contact Research Services.
  - Personal Files Series
    - American Boards (Box 1)
    - Beulaville, N.C. (Box 1)
    - Business Letters 1962-1964 (Box 1)
    - Business Letters, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Business Letters, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Business Letter, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Business Letters, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Business Letters, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Business Letters, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Business Letters, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Business Letters, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Central Prison (Box 1)
    - Charleston, S.C. (Box 1)
    - Draft Board (Box 1)
    - Duke Endowment (Box 1)
    - Durham-Orange County Medical Society, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Educational Foundation (Box 1)
    - Jacksonville, N.C. (Box 2)
    - Letters from Camp (Box 2)
    - N.C. Medical Board (Box 2)
    - Office Plans - Chapel Hill, N.C. (Box 2)
    - Personal Correspondence, undated, 1961-1963 (Box 2)